I would now like to
Speaker 1: recognize the gentleman from Michigan and our subcommittee vice chairman, Mr. Amash, for five minutes. Thank
you, Mr. Chair,
Speaker 2: and thank you to the panel for being here. And, Mr. Donahoe, I
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): really enjoyed meeting you the other day and chatting with you. Thank you. You had just said, I think, that you guys would break even if you didn't
have to make
The
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): pre-funding? This year, yes. But I think your own plan shows that you would have an operating income loss.
Our
Speaker 5 (lower-pitched voice): plan shows an operating income loss of about $900 million, but we will continue to cut. We have got a plan in place right now. We are addressing administrative cost reduction, $750 million. We will get some of that this year. We have got some other changes going.
Speaker 5 (lower-pitched voice): our goal would be to make $100 million this year if we were able to be
Speaker 6: forgiven from the prepayment plan this year.
I
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): have a copy of the letter from the Office of Personnel Management to former Postmaster General John Potter. It is from September 2004, and it rejects the claim that USPS has overpaid the civil service system, civil service retirement system.
OPM
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): explains that the Postal Service's request for a return of $75 billion in overpayment to the CSRS is unfounded and should not be granted by the Congress. Furthermore, the letter includes a statement from the CSRS Board of Actuaries in which it declares that OPM has appropriately and accurately determined the financial obligations for the Postal Service. Mr. Chair, I ask unanimous consent to submit this letter for the record.
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): Mr. Donahoe, what is your response to the letter? Here is my response. We have
Speaker 5 (lower-pitched voice): differing opinions here. Our IG and the Postal Service has estimated with external actuaries that we have overpaid $75 billion. The Postal Regulatory Commission has looked at the same information, and their outside actuaries have estimated that we have overpaid somewhere between $50 and $55. So there is a meeting of the minds necessary to sit down and get this resolved once and for all.
So
Speaker 5 (lower-pitched voice): you do disagree with the
Speaker 7: letter? I disagree with the letter.
Speaker 8: If I could add
Speaker 9: that the PAEA actually
has a
Speaker 9: provision so that the Postal Service can ask us to review the OPM analysis. The Postal Regulatory Commission did what we believe is an objective analysis, bringing in a highly respected third party expert to review the situation.
So
Speaker 9: one could say you have the self-interest of the Postal Service and the self-interest of the Office of Personnel Management, each one wanting to protect its funds. But I want to assure you that the Postal Regulatory Commission had no preconceptions, gave this study no prior directions, and we came up with what we believe is a fair and objective assessment that there is, in fact, a $50 billion overpayment
there.
And
Speaker 10: without objection, the letter so referenced is entered in the record.
I have a
Speaker 11: question for Mr.
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): Herr, as well. In your testimony, you recognize that a significant financial issue for the Postal Service is the fact that 80 percent of its costs go toward employee salaries and benefits. Do you believe that USPS should be able to renegotiate collective bargaining agreements?
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): One area that we suggested that Congress reconsider is whether contracts that go to binding arbitration, if there is an impasse, that there be a consideration given to the Postal Service's ability to pay
Speaker 13: and given its financial situation. So that is an area that we have highlighted in prior work and I highlighted again today in my statement.
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): And the President has suggested giving USPS some breathing room. Will that actually make the
Speaker 14: problem worse by delaying
it?
I would
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): say that one of the things we have been on the record as saying the Postal Service needed some short-term relief for this retiree health care benefit payment, we have been saying that for two years. This would be a third year. I think this is really the time we are at the statutory debt limit to make some hard decisions about what this organization is going to look like going forward.
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): Your overall liabilities and obligations outlined in my statement are over $100 billion now. So it is time to take into consideration the changing use
of the mail,
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): what kind of footprint the Postal Service needs, and then really think about how that is all going to be paid for, including retiree benefits, which employees are expecting to.
Thank you all for
Speaker 15: your testimony. I yield back. Thank you.